Brecht Forum Records TAM.635
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Brecht Forum Records
1960s-2013
TAM.635
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
38.0 linear feet in 30 record cartons and 6 oversize boxes (mostly uhaul moving boxes, some plastic boxes)
This collection contains the files of The Brecht Forum, a Marxist cultural and educational center based in Brooklyn, New York. Founded in 1975 as the New York Marxist School, The Brecht Forum offers community based educational programs such as public lectures and seminars, art exhibitions, performances, popular education workshops, and language classes. Materials contained within this collection include Brecht Forum newspapers, event flyers, correspondence, photographs, programming files, minutes and reports from the New York Marxist School and Marxist Education Collective, and audio cassette recordings of conference events and lectures.
Arrangement
The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Brecht Forum, named after German writer Bertolt Brecht, is an independent Marxist educational and cultural center based in Brooklyn, New York. Founded as the New York Marxist School in 1975, it later incorporated as the Brecht Forum in 1984 to include a broader range of educational and artistic programs. The New York Marxist School remained the Forum's core project, but it has since expanded to include additional projects like the Institute for Popular Education, founded in 1990 in collaboration with the Theater of the Oppressed Laboratory & Arts at the Brecht. The Brecht Forum offers programs designed to promote critical analysis of capitalist society through programs such as public lectures and seminars, art exhibitions, performances, popular education workshops, and language classes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Brecht Forum sent a gift of its organizational records in 2013. The accession number associated with this gift is 2013.025.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the files of the Brecht Forum, a Marxist educational institution based in Brooklyn, New York. The materials in this collection include: Brecht Forum newspapers; flyers for events hosted by Brecht Forum; correspondence; photographs; files related to programming and educational courses; minutes and reports from the New York Marxist School and Marxist Education Collective; and audio cassette recordings of conference events and lectures.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Appraisal note
No materials were separated from this collection.
Mestres, Liz; New York Marxist School.
- Cassette Tapes, 1970s-1990s (Box 1-3)
- Cassette Tapes, 1980s-2000s (Box 4)
- Cassette Tapes, 1970s-2000s (Box 5)
- Betacam Tapes (some labeled "Manifestivity," referring to Brecht Forum's 150th anniversary celebration of the Communist Manifesto), circa 1998 (Box 6)
- Cassette Tapes (original box labeled "BAC 99"), 1990s-2000s (Box 7)
- Correspondence - A through C, 1980s-2010s (Box 8)
- Correspondence - C through H, 1980s-2010s (Box 9)
- Correspondence - H through M, 1980s-2010s (Box 10)
- Correspondence - M through R, 1980s-2010s (Box 11)
- Correspondence - R through T, 1980s-2010s (Box 12)
- Correspondence - U through Z, and Annette Rubenstein Papers and Photographs, 1960s-2010s (Box 13)
- Cassette Tapes, 1990s-2000s (Box 14)
- Publicity/Program Calendars and Programming Files re: July Intensive School, 1970s-2010s (Box 15)
- Programming Files re: July Intensive School and Marxist Education Conferences, 1970s-1990s (Box 16)
- Programming and Subject Files, 1970s-1990s (Box 17-20)
- Programming Files re: Faculty Meetings, Arts Programming, Brecht Forum History, etc., 1980s-1990s (Box 21)
- Programming and Subject Files, circa 1980-1999 (Box 22-23)
- Programming and Subject Files, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 24)
- Programming Files, 1990s-2000s (Box 25)
- Programming and Fundraising Files, 1990s-2000s (Box 26)
- Fundraising Files, 1990s-2000s (Box 27-28)
- Fundraising Files, 1980s-2000s (Box 29)
- Programming and Fundraising Files, 1970s-1990s (Box 30)
- Cassette Tapes, 1970s-2000s (Box 31)
- Cassette Tapes, 1980s (Box 32)
- Cassette Tapes, 1980s-2000s (Box 33)
- Cassette Tapes, 1970s-1990s (Box 34)
- New Marxist School - Catalogs, Reports etc., NY Committee on Marxist Education Minutes, Marxist Education Collective- Minutes, Reports etc., 1975-1999 (Box 35)
- Marxist Education Collective - Minutes, Reports etc., NY Marxist School - Minutes Notebook, School Info. etc., Brecht Forum event fliers, 1970-1985 (Box 36)
- School of Marxist Education Course Materials and Event Fliers, 1970s-1992 (Box 37)
- School of Marxist Education Course Materials, 1974-1982 (Box 38)
- Brecht Forum Newspapers, 1999-2004 (Box 39)